<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thulika on Sinu John</title>
    <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/tags/thulika/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thulika on Sinu John</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sinujohn.github.io/tags/thulika/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP Thulika Keyboard.. (sob).. (sob)</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/12/rip-thulika-keyboard-sob-sob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/12/rip-thulika-keyboard-sob-sob/</guid>
      <description>Just got to know that Google has came up with an handwriting recognition app - Google Handwriting Input.
And the good part is it has got Indian language support. Yay!!
But the bad part is that, it means the demise of my very own Thulika Keyboard. I had created it about 2 years back, and at that time there was no handwriting recognition app for any Indian language. I also had opensourced it, and have got requests from many to translate it to their language(Arabic, Hausa, Tamil to name a few) and some even have used it as part of their school/college projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected newspaper article!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/08/14/unexpected-newspaper-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/08/14/unexpected-newspaper-article/</guid>
      <description>Today I was scanning through Malayala Manorama and then I saw an article which mentions my Thulika Kayboard. The article appears in Malayala Manorama of 14th August 2013 (Padippura section). I saw it in Thiruvananthapuram edition and don&amp;rsquo;t know whether other editions have it.
Here is the article:

&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opensourced Thulika</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/03/05/opensourced-thulika/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/03/05/opensourced-thulika/</guid>
      <description>I just opensourced the Thulika Keyboard app and the associated training softwares. Find it here on Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff tweeted Thulika!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/02/08/jeff-tweeted-thulika/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/02/08/jeff-tweeted-thulika/</guid>
      <description>The developer of Encog library, Jeff Heaton, tweeted about my first Android app - Thulika Keyboard. Someone wrote a nice Android handwriting app with #encog. https://t.co/vd2JpTrR
&amp;mdash; jeffheaton (@jeffheaton) February 2, 2013  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thulika Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/01/21/thulika-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/01/21/thulika-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Download the app from PlayStore On January 6th early morning(at about 3 AM), I created my Google Developer account, and published my first Android app - Thulika Keyboard - in the Play Store. Thulika Keyboard is a Handwriting recognition keyboard. It is the first app that brings handwriting recognition to an Indian Language(Malayalam for the time being!). User writes a single symbol, the app recognizes it and may give a possible list of suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training the Thulika Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/01/14/training-the-thulika-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/01/14/training-the-thulika-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Before you read :
Indian languages use complex script unlike English letters. Each English letter is composed of a single Unicode letter. But each letter of Indian languages may be composed of more than one Unicode letters.
The decomposition is as follows: LetterCode + modifyingSymbolCode
Eg: ക്രൊ = ( ക + ്ര + ൊ )
So as you see the code that comes first(ക) need not be the first letter that the user writes(െ).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>