<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Sinu John</title>
    <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Sinu John</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sinujohn.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost and a look back on C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/01/20/boost-and-a-look-back-on-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/01/20/boost-and-a-look-back-on-c/</guid>
      <description>These days am a full time Java guy and the last time I coded in C++ was a little over an year ago. It was then I came across Boost library and I had heard that it packed a lot under the 5 letter library BOOST. Even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t much used Boost, since it is being made part of the C++ standard, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be a person who knew legacy C++ and so was always keen to know about Boost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Namesake</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/11/08/the-namesake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/11/08/the-namesake/</guid>
      <description>One of the best novels i have ever read - The Namesake. Loved it. Awesome work by Jhumpa Lahiri. Following is a quote I have found to be very inspiring
 &amp;ldquo;Do yourself a favor. Before it&amp;rsquo;s too late, without thinking too much about it first, pack a pillow and a blanket and see as much of the world as you can. You will not regret it. One day it will be too late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thrown into the ebook bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/16/thrown-into-the-ebook-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/16/thrown-into-the-ebook-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have started reading a lot of books. And by recently, I mean the last two weeks. And these books are not ordinary paperback books, but they are ebooks which I read on my Nexus 7. I never thought I will be reading ebooks - I thought this was just a hype and ebooks can&#39;t just give you that feel that you get while reading a hardcopy of the book, I always thought I will miss the turning of pages, the smell of new books, the look of old books, but alas, I haven&#39;t started to miss much of these!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>