<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bike on Hack</title>
    <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/tags/bike/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bike on Hack</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://sinujohn.github.io/tags/bike/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Skandagiri</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/08/27/skandagiri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/08/27/skandagiri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About two months back, me and a friend of mine went for trekking at Skandagiri Hills. Its about 75km from Bangalore near to Nandi Hills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m29!1m12!1m3!1d497214.8001609372!2d77.65143103991002!3d13.194484654410234!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m14!1i0!3e6!4m5!1s0x3bae123e25555555%3A0x695a1bc21346928a!2sDialatron+Telecom+Private+Limited%2C+No+1%2C+28%2F2%2C+Regent+Place%2C+Thubarahalli+Village%2C+Thubarahalli+Village%2C+Bengaluru%2C+Karnataka+560066!3m2!1d12.954193!2d77.72160099999999!4m5!1s0x3bb1e58ea2581285%3A0xd1e16751dc57a045!2sSkandagiri%2C+Suddahalli%2C+Karnataka+562103!3m2!1d13.417499999999999!2d77.682778!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sin!4v1409125768190&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started on my Yamaha Fz at about 2:30AM and reached there by 4.30AM. The place has got a few locals who are waiting there to get hold of your money in the form of parking and acting as guide! We parked (gave the guy Rs20/30 just to make sure he don&#39;t destroy my bike) and dismissed the idea of having a guide. The trek started and we reached the top by 5.15 in the morning. The view was awesome!&lt;br /&gt; Here is a map of the area and route to be taken. It&#39;ll save you the cost of having a guide and give you a sense of adventure as you are finding way through pitch dark (if there is no moonlight ;)). Remember to take a good torchlight and a jacket. It&#39;ll be very cold at the top. Its an easy trek. Once you find the muddy lane you can easily reach the top - you don&#39;t require any guide! There is a small catch though - there is a route which you shouldn&#39;t take - its marked in red colour. This red route is considerably wider and it reaches a dead-end! But what&#39;s the fun if there is no thrill in finding the right way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sinujohn.github.io/assets/skandagiri_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;skandagiri&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We started back by 10 in the morning. On the way back we stopped at a small Fort near Nandi hills - Fort Devanahalli. Took some pictures and then headed back to Bengaluru!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thiruvananthapuram Life</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/29/thiruvananthapuram-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/29/thiruvananthapuram-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For almost two years I am living in Thiruvananthapuram(from March 2012 to be exact). And in these past few months I have travelled a lot in and around Thiruvananthapuram.
Do I love this place? Yes and No.
No? Why? Because this place lacks some sort of energy :(
And yes because, there are a lot of places in and around Thiruvananthapuram, that provides some sort of ancient ambience. The backwaters like Muthalapozhi, the old buildings in the locality of Sree Padmanabha Swami Temple, the green hot spots of the city like Museum, Zoo and Kanakakunnu Palace (where I spent a lot of time in the weekends), the cultural hot spots like Nishagandhi Ground, Vyloppilli Samskriti Bhavan and the reader&amp;rsquo;s paradise - the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trivandrum_Public_library&#34;&gt;Trivandrum Public Library&lt;/a&gt; (where I am a member and which made me a voracious reader once again) are some spots that I will definitly miss if I leave Thiruvananthapuram.
The bike trips that I have done around this place is close to 10000 km!
The following map show some of the short distance trips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m76!1m12!1m3!1d267521.8636949016!2d76.80008028469128!3d8.555347941141372!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m61!3e0!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!4m5!1s0x3b05a5960e90dc0f%3A0x6c20be6dc7c83670!2sKovalam+Light+house%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.3829317!2d76.9796703!4m5!1s0x0%3A0x60cdff4235654bb9!2sVizhinjam+Juma+Masjid!3m2!1d8.3766123!2d76.9865183!4m5!1s0x3b05bb6774e1149b%3A0x1efe85dbc5053198!2sValiathura+Beach!3m2!1d8.464157!2d76.92454149999999!4m5!1s0x3b05bc83dedcfc07%3A0xc899203065f19098!2sShangumugham+Beach%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.4784498!2d76.9119061!4m5!1s0x3b05bc3b8bcd7c63%3A0xf2a956af86a27253!2sVeli+Lake+and+Tourist+Village%2C+Veli+Sanghumugham+Road%2C+Veli%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5080206!2d76.88867019999999!4m5!1s0x3b05ef1c47000001%3A0x28d32906ae208476!2sPapanasam+Beach%2C+Varkala%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.7327015!2d76.70605669999999!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!4m5!1s0x3b05c95ff9740455%3A0x74aefbb63ac4f952!2sVazhvanthol+Waterfalls%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.6745608!2d77.1633027!4m5!1s0x3b05cdc56677fbd3%3A0xb9400a2604d8f63d!2sPonmudi+Hill+Station%2C+Ponmudi%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.7577585!2d77.1157944!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1489429824438&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are the long distance trips :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to &lt;a href=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}{% post_url 2012-09-01-a-trip-to-the-southernmost-tip %}&#34;&gt;Kanyakumari&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&#34;{{ site.baseurl }}{% post_url 2013-03-11-agastyakoodam-trekking %}&#34;&gt;Agastyarkoodam&lt;/a&gt; and to Thenkasi (via Thenmala and Palaruvi waterfalls)
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m72!1m8!1m3!1d1009750.7718668396!2d77.088097!3d8.659278!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m61!3e0!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction%2C+NH+47+Bypass%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala+695582%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!4m5!1s0x3b05af5b949c96d9%3A0x82c2dfa6dffb751c!2sPoovar+-+Vizhinjam+Rd%2C+Karumkulam%2C+Kerala+695525%2C+India!3m2!1d8.3271391!2d77.0560321!4m5!1s0x3b0454f79775f7c3%3A0x86b55a2e872ecd32!2sChitral+Rock+Temple%2C+Vellamcode%2C+Tamil+Nadu+629151%2C+India!3m2!1d8.3323779!2d77.2384304!4m5!1s0x3b05af5b949c96d9%3A0x82c2dfa6dffb751c!2sPoovar+-+Vizhinjam+Rd%2C+Karumkulam%2C+Kerala+695525%2C+India!3m2!1d8.3194559!2d77.0655432!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction%2C+NH+47+Bypass%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala+695582%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!4m5!1s0x3b05bf3cc78b105b%3A0xe2d7c8ffbb9798b!2sUnknown%2C+Uliyazhathura%2C+Kerala+695581%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5785933!2d76.8994874!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction%2C+NH+47+Bypass%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala+695582%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!4m5!1s0x3b05d628ce443a95%3A0x21700d924118d43c!2sThenmala%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.9632448!2d77.0650809!4m5!1s0x3b05d570afa845b3%3A0x9ad29897133245dc!2sPalaruvi+Waterfalls%2C+Road+to+Palaruvi+Waterfalls%2C+Kollam%2C+Kerala%2C+India!3m2!1d8.952378699999999!2d77.15484479999999!4m5!1s0x3b0429c15ac547f7%3A0x9a707276cd8ae327!2sTenkasi%2C+Tamil+Nadu%2C+India!3m2!1d8.9590214!2d77.3129383!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1489426569264&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m42!1m8!1m3!1d1010633.21746241!2d77.227604!3d8.324051!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m31!3e0!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction%2C+NH+47+Bypass%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala+695582%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!4m5!1s0x3be7e7d457af298f%3A0xf816a5f8d82383ff!2sPanvel+-+Kochi+-+Kanyakumari+Hwy%2C+Vettunimadam%2C+Nagercoil%2C+Tamil+Nadu+629001%2C+India!3m2!1d8.179677!2d77.421188!4m5!1s0x3b04f51233a9b575%3A0xada29bbad5cd14c2!2sMuppandal+Wind+Farm%2C+Aralvaimozhi%2C+Tamil+Nadu+627105%2C+India!3m2!1d8.2616075!2d77.54175599999999!4m5!1s0x3b04ed3d2a087861%3A0x1e790e896aeffaa0!2sKanyakumari%2C+Tamil+Nadu%2C+India!3m2!1d8.0883064!2d77.5384507!4m5!1s0x3b05beffd4dcd581%3A0x10321bb1abc84324!2sKazhakoottam+Junction%2C+NH+47+Bypass%2C+Thiruvananthapuram%2C+Kerala+695582%2C+India!3m2!1d8.5657443!2d76.8748999!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1489426740046&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelling these routes one time alone is around 1000 kilometres! :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trip to the Southernmost tip</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2012/09/01/a-trip-to-the-southernmost-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2012/09/01/a-trip-to-the-southernmost-tip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We planned to start to Kanyakumari from Thiruvanathapuram(tvm) by 5 AM so that we could see the sun rise at India&amp;rsquo;s southern-most tip. But as usual, we got
delayed! And we left by about 5.45AM. Our rides consisted of my Fz and a friend&amp;rsquo;s Hunk. There were 4 of us - Arun Elias, Dhanoop Bhaskar, Basil Kuriakose and
myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode through Kanyakumari-Panvel road. We reached Neyyattinkara and had breakfast from a small hotel. We crossed Amaravila checkpost and very soon the
surroundings started to resemble Tamil Nadu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By about 8 we were only half way when we reached this place:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://sinujohn.github.io/assets/kanyakumari.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Three&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a little after the Kumaracoil junction. Here we saw beautiful peaks that touched the clouds. The moment we saw this we changed our route. And we reached
Mambazhathuraiyar Resevoir. (To reach this place: after Kumaracoil junction, drive on the Kanyakumari route, you&amp;rsquo;ll see an overbridge(actually an aquaduct),
and just before that on to the left you can see the road that leads to the reservoir). The road goes through a very beautiful place. We spent some time at
the reservoir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim was the top of the peak so we kept going in that direction. We saw Noorul Islam Engineering College and took the right turn that immediately follows
it. This road went high up till it almost reached a dead end. Here there was a small temple. After this, there was no more road as such. But there was a
muddy lane which went steeply up. After about 400 metres I found a gate on which it was written- Naga Hills. Here we found a Malayali, who was generous
enough to allow us to bath in a small forest lake-cum-waterfall (it was on his property). He also said many stories and places to see around that area. It
was he who gave us our next location - Kaattadi hills/Mt.Devasahayam. But we couldn&amp;rsquo;t reach the top of the hill. There was no road that led there and we had to trek about 4km. Since we didn&amp;rsquo;t carry any food with us, we dropped that plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the trekking we continued our journey. We took a left turn at Nagercoil(actually before Nagercoil, even though we meant to take the left at Nagercoil), and rode in Thirunelveli route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 15km we reached Mt.Devasahayam. It was here that Vedasakshi Devasahayam Pilla got killed. Above this hill, there is a rock, which produces the
sound of a bell. Legend is that, Mr.Pilla was killed by a King for being a Christian. He was killed on this hill. No one knew about this murder. Then a rock
fell and a clinging noise was heard throughout the forest. The villagers nearby inspected the place and found the dead man. Its this rock thats preserved
over here. We did strike the rock with small stones, and it did produce bell sound!
From above Mt.Devasahayam we saw hundreds of wind mills. So our next destination was Kanya Spin(I can&amp;rsquo;t find this place in Google Maps, but it seems to be
Muppandal Wind Farm). And after reaching that place, we were awestruck. We didn&amp;rsquo;t imagine that thing to be so huge! The place had very little trees and the
wind was blowing at a high speed. After spending some time there, we started off to Kanyakumari by about 3.30PM!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode to Kanyakumari on Thirunelveli-Kanyakumari route(NH7 that leads connects Kanyakumari and Salem). There are no words to describe that ride. The road
is simply superb! We were welcomed by wind mills on both sides for some distance. The wind was so strong that sometimes we were almost blown away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally we reached Kanyakumari by 4.15PM. But alas, we coudn&amp;rsquo;t get to Vivekananda rock, as tickets are issued only till 4PM. But we had more than what we
thought we would have on that trip. We spent some time at Kanyakumari. Almost dozed off watching the sea. Saw the sunset at one of the world&amp;rsquo;s rarest places
(the place where 3 seas merge). And finally took the return ride at about 8PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 204km trip we had imagined went to 264km by the time we reached our rooms!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In this trip we didn&amp;rsquo;t go to the usual tourist locations like Padmanabhapuram Palace, Fort etc. We coudn&amp;rsquo;t find time! Instead we gladly explored the village/hilly areas)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>