<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants on Sinu John</title>
    <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/categories/rants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants on Sinu John</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 15:14:34 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sinujohn.github.io/categories/rants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From wordpress to github</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2017/03/27/from-wordpress-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 15:14:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2017/03/27/from-wordpress-to-github/</guid>
      <description>It has been more than 6 months since I have blogged! I just shifted all my blog posts from my Wordpress blog to github. First I used Jekyll. Setting it up was a pain on my Windows PC. It needed Ruby and all those extra Rubygems. Then I settled for the Jekyll Docker image. That was better, but still generating the 70-odd-posts took so long everytime, and I knew it&amp;rsquo;ll take longer as the number of posts increase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Developer Personality</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/21/my-developer-personality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/21/my-developer-personality/</guid>
      <description>I took a Developer Personality Test, conducted by DZoneand it almost sums up what I am! Here&amp;rsquo;s the result I got:
Collaborative:Good code doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen in a vacuum. You need a team to keep you energized and on your toes so that you&amp;rsquo;re constantly improving the project code using the entire team&amp;rsquo;s varied experience and strengths. You like to talk frequently with colleagues and discuss ideas so that you can learn from others and spark ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP Thulika Keyboard.. (sob).. (sob)</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/12/rip-thulika-keyboard-sob-sob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/12/rip-thulika-keyboard-sob-sob/</guid>
      <description>Just got to know that Google has came up with an handwriting recognition app - Google Handwriting Input.
And the good part is it has got Indian language support. Yay!!
But the bad part is that, it means the demise of my very own Thulika Keyboard. I had created it about 2 years back, and at that time there was no handwriting recognition app for any Indian language. I also had opensourced it, and have got requests from many to translate it to their language(Arabic, Hausa, Tamil to name a few) and some even have used it as part of their school/college projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wait... But... Why?</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/12/wait-but-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/12/wait-but-why/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t always subscribe to blogs..
But when its about nicely written articles about science, technology and all the cool things that I usually want to read about, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t, I am like: I have become a fan of http://waitbutwhy.com/just after reading an article about Elon Muskand one about Fermi Paradox</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmer Zen</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/04/programmer-zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/05/04/programmer-zen/</guid>
      <description>Just read this quoteand I loved it:
Realizing this problem, the programmer will start to spend a lot of time thinking about structure. Her programs will be rigidly structured, like rock sculptures. They are solid, but when they must change, violence must be done to them.
The master programmer knows when to apply structure and when to leave things in their simple form. Her programs are like clay, solid yet malleable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>angamaly-marakkamo</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/03/10/angamaly-marakkamo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2015/03/10/angamaly-marakkamo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hearing it from the granpa!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/07/17/hearing-it-from-the-granpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/07/17/hearing-it-from-the-granpa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First half of 2014</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/07/08/first-half-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/07/08/first-half-of-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings of a Windows-using Linux fan!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/07/08/musings-of-a-windows-using-linux-fan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/07/08/musings-of-a-windows-using-linux-fan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/06/19/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/06/19/debugging/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRM-free content</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/05/06/drm-free-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2014/05/06/drm-free-content/</guid>
      <description>These days all publishers are worried about their rights and the books are locked in, which is especially problematic in this digital age. Because unlike old days where we could share a book(hardcopy) which we bought, the new avatar of books - the e-books - are increasingly made to be under DRM, which means it stays only on one device or person. It can&amp;rsquo;t be shared with our friends even if we bought it with our hard earned cash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Namesake</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/11/08/the-namesake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/11/08/the-namesake/</guid>
      <description>One of the best novels i have ever read - The Namesake. Loved it. Awesome work by Jhumpa Lahiri. Following is a quote I have found to be very inspiring
Now I have started reading her another book - &amp;ldquo;The interpreter of maladies&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thiruvananthapuram Life</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/29/thiruvananthapuram-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/29/thiruvananthapuram-life/</guid>
      <description>For almost two years I am living in Thiruvananthapuram(from March 2012 to be exact). And in these past few months I have travelled a lot in and around Thiruvananthapuram. Do I love this place? Yes and No. No? Why? Because this place lacks some sort of energy :( And yes because, there are a lot of places in and around Thiruvananthapuram, that provides some sort of ancient ambience. The backwaters like Muthalapozhi, the old buildings in the locality of Sree Padmanabha Swami Temple, the green hot spots of the city like Museum, Zoo and Kanakakunnu Palace (where I spent a lot of time in the weekends), the cultural hot spots like Nishagandhi Ground, Vyloppilli Samskriti Bhavan and the reader&amp;rsquo;s paradise - the Trivandrum Public Library(where I am a member and which made me a voracious reader once again) are some spots that I will definitly miss if I leave Thiruvananthapuram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thrown into the ebook bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/16/thrown-into-the-ebook-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/16/thrown-into-the-ebook-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am an INTP</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/11/i-am-an-intp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/10/11/i-am-an-intp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Nexus 7</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/09/23/my-new-nexus-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/09/23/my-new-nexus-7/</guid>
      <description>After what seemed like a long wait, I finally got my own Nexus7 2nd generation. Am now playing with the device and the first impression is IT IS AWESOME! A good friend of mine asked her family who was flying down from the US to get it for me. The device landed last week but I got my hands on it only today as I was on a vacation last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google, Y U NO???</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/08/31/google-y-u-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/08/31/google-y-u-no/</guid>
      <description>I had been waiting for Google&amp;rsquo;s new Nexus 7 to be launched in India since it was released in late July. But seems like we Indians have to wait till year end:(
I created this meme since I can&amp;rsquo;t control the feeling any longer! aaahh.. now it feels better! :D ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected newspaper article!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/08/14/unexpected-newspaper-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/08/14/unexpected-newspaper-article/</guid>
      <description>Today I was scanning through Malayala Manorama and then I saw an article which mentions my Thulika Kayboard. The article appears in Malayala Manorama of 14th August 2013 (Padippura section). I saw it in Thiruvananthapuram edition and don&amp;rsquo;t know whether other editions have it.
Here is the article:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff tweeted Thulika!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/02/08/jeff-tweeted-thulika/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2013/02/08/jeff-tweeted-thulika/</guid>
      <description>The developer of Encoglibrary, Jeff Heaton, tweeted about my first Android app - Thulika Keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legendary Jobs!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2011/10/06/legendary-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2011/10/06/legendary-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Woke up today (actually yesterday as its past 12 midnight) to hear the news of Steve Jobs&amp;rsquo; death. The news about the death of a man whom I consider one of my role models actually left a kind of pain. Yup, I felt sad, as if someone I knew had died :(
I am not a user of Apple products. But I have used them though. Its not from the Apple-user perspective that I like this man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerdy Jokes ;)</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2011/01/20/nerdy-jokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2011/01/20/nerdy-jokes/</guid>
      <description>Just happened to read some &amp;lsquo;nerdy&amp;rsquo; jokes here.
My favourite ones (credit goes to their respective creators):
The Physicist says, &amp;ldquo;Well there is obviously an unknown variable.&amp;rdquo; The Biologist says, &amp;ldquo;The man must have multiplied.&amp;rdquo;
The mathematician then looks at them both and says, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how it happened but if one more person enters the house it will be empty.&amp;ldquo; The first asks for a beer. The second asks for half a beer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://sinujohn.github.io/2010/03/26/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinujohn.github.io/2010/03/26/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Decided to keep the default title for the first post.So &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; :)
Have started three/four blogs in the past. But couldn&amp;rsquo;t stick with them. Atleast i think i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t abandon this one. First reason is i got this blog with my name. And the second one is i really get a feeling that i should be sincere with this one. And the third one is &amp;hellip; hmm.. oops.. no third one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>